PETER AUGROS

2701 E LINVALE PL, DENVER, CO 80210

(303) 668-1940 | peteraugros@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/peter-augros-66269216/peteraugros.com https://www.quora.com/profile/Peter-Augros

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Charismatic and dependable Teacher with 20 years of experience delivering educational assistance and instruction to various levels of learners. Committed to providing students with necessary tools to achieve academic goals, instilling a love of learning and cooperative teamwork. Adept in application of excellent communication and problem solving skills.

SKILLS

Instructional design
Educational leadership Staff
development Positive
reinforcement Curriculum
Development Lesson
Planning Instructional
Design Higher Education
Adult Education
Technological savvy

Public Speaking
Educational Leadership
College preparation
Spanish Latin Piano
Meditation Javascript,
HTML, CSS Classroom
management Typing 80
WPM

WORK HISTORY

MULLEN HIGH SCHOOL High School Teacher | Denver, CO |

October 2005 - October 2018

Devised and implemented course instructional plans to teach Philosophy, Theology, Latin, Mathematics, Computer Science, Chess, and Creative Writing for thousands of over a period of twenty years, while meeting or exceeding district standards. Selected and requisitioned appropriate books and instructional aids to complement lesson plans. Assessed students' strengths and weaknesses regularly to provide appropriate methods for addressing learning needs. Implemented different technologies to engage students in class instruction and

diversify approaches. Talked with students in need of extra attention and made plans to assist with concerns. Maintained communication with parents Inspired academic success based on belief that all students can achieve excellence, regardless of background. Created engaging, inspirational and relevant lesson plans, fostering a culture of discovery and provided well-organized classroom structure to help students succeed in the program. Evaluated academic performance and social relationships to identify and help struggling students. Worked with other teachers for comprehensive approach to education.

ST. THOMAS MORE *Middle School Youth Minister* | *Denver, CO* | *August 2002 - August 2005*

Taught and counseled youth ages 10 to 18. Scheduled and managed teams of youth volunteers. Built lasting relationships with youth and parents or guardians through youth programs and retreats. Oversaw youth ministry budget and tracked all expenses. Shared valuable life experiences with youths aged 10 to 18 to promote positive self-esteem and improve social skills. Planned weekly groups as well as special events and overnight retreats. Oversaw administration and management of all areas of ministry including facilities. Organized and spearheaded community outreach programs, including shadowing and mentor programs focused on helping middle school students plan for college or vocational education opportunities and participate in local civic processes. Provided spiritual care through visitation, counseling and prayer. Planned and hosted on- and off-campus community service activities.

EDUCATION

MASTER OF ARTS Philosophy And Humanities Universita Pontificia Regina Apostolorum *Rome, Italy* | 2000

HIGH SCHOOL DIPLOMA

Merrimack High School *Merrimack, NH* | *1995*

CHESS, PIANO, MEDITATION

Chess teacher, coach, business owner, and author with over 35 years experience Self taught piano player and performer 30+ years meditation experience 5 years meditation coaching 1600+ answers on Spirituality and Meditation on Quora.com

NOTA BENE

I was studying to be a Catholic Priest from 1994 - 2002 with vows of poverty, chastity, and obedience which brought me all over the United States and Mexico